# TADESSE JEMAL

# FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

tadessejemal63@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

I'm an experienced front-end developer who enjoys working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. I'm also an accomplished Front End web Developer with 1-year experience designing online assets to attract maximum engagement and conversions from any placement.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools. Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication skills.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Front End Web Developer

Remote

September 2021 – Present

Todo-list-App — This project is a user who adds lists of tasks, and the website has features of editing, deleting, and storing the data in local storage.

- HTML,CSS3,JavaScript
- Live link

Awesome-Books — website containing a list of books that can be modified by adding or removing a book Re-create the Awesome books app using ES6 syntax.

- HTML, CSS3, JavaScript
- <u>live link</u>

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

August 2022 – Present

- Mentor junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Propose improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provide advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

BahirDar, Ethiopia

January 2020 - December 2021

## UI/UX Designer

- Illustrated design ideas using storyboards, process flows, or sitemaps.
- Designed five websites using Figma.
- Created six mobile apps for safety videos.

### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE July 2022– present

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 7 months mastering algorithms, data structures, and website development and developing projects with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Database, Ruby, and Rails.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.